Hey everyone, and welcome. Today, we are going to unlock a phrase that's basically a social
皆さん、こんにちは。今日は、英語の 社交的なスーパーパワーを紹介します。
superpower in English. Seriously, it's super simple, but it's so powerful, and it's going
本当にシンプルですが、とても強力で、 コミュニケーションが変わります。
to completely change how you communicate. You ready? Let's jump right in.
準備はいいですか？さっそく始めましょう。
First things first, let's talk about a word you use all the time. Want. It's probably
まずは、よく使う言葉について話しましょう。 「Want」です。
one of the very first English words you learned, but have you ever kind of worried that
おそらく、最初に覚えた英単語の一つですが、 時々失礼に聞こえないか心配したことはありますか？
it might sound a little rude sometimes? Let's figure out why picking the right
正しい言葉を選ぶことがなぜ重要なのか、 考えてみましょう。
That word is so, so important. Okay, picture this.
想像してみてください。
You walk into a pizza shop in America.
アメリカのピザ屋に入ります。
You're super hungry and you go up to the counter and say, I want a pizza.
お腹が空いて、カウンターに行って「I want a pizza」と言います。
Now is that wrong? Well, not really, they'll totally understand you.
それは間違いですか？ まあ、そうではありません。理解してもらえます。
But it can sound a little demanding, you know, almost like how a little kid might talk to
でも、少し要求的に聞こえるかもしれません。 子供が親に話すような感じです。
their parents.
親しい友達には問題ありませんが、
With your best friend it's no big deal, but in most other situations, we can do
他の多くの状況では、もっと良い言い方があります。 これが大事な文化的ポイントです。
way better. And this gets to a really huge cultural point.
英語圏、特にアメリカでは、 日常の場面で礼儀正しさが重要です。
In English-speaking countries, especially in the US, being polite in just normal, everyday
敬意を示すことが大切で、 適切な言葉を選ぶことで、礼儀正しく聞こえます。
situations is a really big deal.
それだけでなく、より成熟し、自信があるように聞こえます。
It's all about showing respect, and choosing the right words doesn't just make you sound
では、秘密は何でしょう？
polite. It makes you sound more mature and way more confident.
失礼に聞こえず、子供のように聞こえない お願いの仕方は？
So what's the secret then?
それでは、魔法のフレーズを紹介します。
How can you ask for something without sounding a little bit rude or like a little kid?
それは、すぐに英語力を向上させるフレーズです。 「I would like」です。
Well, it is time to reveal the magic phrase that will instantly level up your English
この3つの言葉が、あなたの新しい親友になります。
skills. And here it is, folks, I would like.
「I want」の代わりに「I would like」と言うだけです。
These three little words are about to become your new best friend.
そうすることで、要求を礼儀正しいお願いに変えられます。
Instead of saying, I want, you just say, I would like.
より思いやりのある印象を与えます。素晴らしいですね。
Just like that, you turn a demand into a polite, respectful request.
さて、要点です。「I want」は直接的でカジュアルです。
And you sound so much more thoughtful. It's awesome.
家族や親しい友人にはぴったりです。
So here's the deal. I want is direct. It's casual.
でも「I would like」は、礼儀正しくて尊重を示します。
It's perfect for your family or your super close friends.
これは、先生や店員、新しい友達に使います。
But I would like, now that's polite and respectful.
ほぼ全ての人に対して安全で賢い選択です。
This is what you're going to use with teachers, people working in shops, new friends, pretty
例えば、「I would like some water」や「I would like some flowers」と言えます。
much everybody else. It is always a safe and really smart choice.
でも、真ん中の例を見てください。「I'd like a sandwich」。
So you could say, I would like some water, or I would like some flowers.
日常会話では、ネイティブスピーカーは「I would」をほとんど「I'd」に短縮します。
But hey, look at that middle example, I'd like a sandwich.
それがより自然に聞こえます。
In real everyday conversation, native speakers almost always shorten I would to I'd.
「I'd like」と言う練習をしてみてください。 プロのように聞こえますよ。
It just sounds so much more natural.
素晴らしいですね。
So practice saying I'd like, and trust me, you're going to sound like a pro.
物を頼むことはマスターしましたが、 誰かに何かをしてもらうお願いはどうでしょう？
Okay, awesome.
例えば、どこかに誘うことです。
So you've totally mastered asking for things, but what about asking people to do something
良いニュースがあります。あなたの新しいスーパーパワーはそれにも使えます。
with you? You know, like inviting them somewhere.
新しい状況を考えてみましょう。
Well, I've got good news. Your new superpower works for that, too.
誕生日です。素晴らしいパーティーを計画しています。
Let's think of a new situation.
友達を招待したいとき、 最初に思いつく言葉は何ですか？
Okay, it's your birthday, you're planning an awesome party.
「Do you want to come to my party?」と言うかもしれません。
You want to invite a friend, what's the first thing that pops in your head to say?
それは全く問題ありません。
You might say this, do you want to come to my party?
明確で、一般的で、友達を招待する良い方法です。
And you know what? That is perfectly fine.
心配しないでください。
It's clear, it's super common, and it's a great way to invite a friend.
間違っているわけではありません。しかし、 スキルを向上させるために、もう少し良い表現にしましょう。
So don't worry.
もっと歓迎するように、 思いやりを持たせましょう。
saying it wrong at all. But hey, since we're here to level up our skills, let's take that
少し特別に感じさせるために。
good sentence and make it even better. Let's make it sound more welcoming, more thoughtful.
こう言います。「Would you like to come to my party?」 違いを感じますか？
Just a little more special.
温かみを感じますよね？ より礼儀正しく、招待が特別な提案に感じられます。
And this is how you do it. Would you like to come to my party? Ah, can you just feel
これが招待の絶対的な基準です。 まとめると、「Do you want」はカジュアルな提案です。
the difference? It feels warmer, right? More polite. It makes the invitation feel like
親友には良いですが、「Would you like?」は 礼儀正しい招待で、誰にでもぴったりです。
a really special offer. This is the absolute gold standard for invitations. So to wrap
新しいクラスメートや先生など、 誰にでも通用します。
that up, do you want is a casual offer. It's great for your best buddies. But would you like?
最後に、このフレーズの強力な使い方があります。 物を頼んだり、招待するだけではありません。
That's a polite invitation and it's perfect for absolutely everyone. A new classmate,
自分の目標や夢について話すときにも使えます。 やりたい行動について話すときは、
a teacher, you name it. It always works.
「I would like to」と言い、動詞を加えます。
This is the perfect way to share your ambitions or what you're planning to do and it sounds
これはあなたの野望や計画を共有するのに最適な方法です。
really thoughtful and mature. For example, you can use it for your biggest dreams like
とても思慮深く、成熟した印象を与えます。例えば、
I'd like to visit London someday or for something simple like I'd like to play tennis this weekend.
「いつかロンドンに行きたい」や「今週末にテニスをしたい」といった夢や
It works for anything you hope to do and it's just a fantastic way to talk about your interests.
希望を表現するのに使えます。あなたの興味について話す素晴らしい方法です。
Okay, let's try building a sentence together real quick. If we follow the path on the
では、さっと一緒に文を作ってみましょう。画面の指示に従うと、
the screen, we get, would you like to go to the zoo with us?
「私たちと一緒に動物園に行きませんか？」になります。
Perfect, see?
完璧ですね。
You're already building these powerful, polite sentences.
もうすでに力強く、丁寧な文を作っています。
It's that easy. Phew, we've covered a lot, so let's bring it all home.
こんなに簡単です。さあ、まとめましょう。
This is your final review so you know exactly when to use Want and when to use your brand
これが最終レビューです。Wantと新しい力であるwould likeの使い方を
new superpower, would like. But wait, first a quick pro tip.
しっかり理解しましょう。でもその前に、ちょっとしたプロのヒントです。
When native speakers say want to really fast, it often sounds like wanna.
ネイティブスピーカーがwantを早口で言うと、wannaのように聞こえます。
Like I wanna watch a movie.
例えば「映画を見たい」と言う時です。
It is super, super common when you're talking with friends.
友達と話す時によく使われます。
But remember this, this is only for speaking, never ever write wana on an English test or
ただし、これは話す時だけの表現で、英語のテストや宿題では絶対に書かないでください。
in your homework. It'll just be our little secret, okay?
私たちの秘密にしましょうね。
So here it is, your ultimate cheat sheet.
これがあなたの究極のチートシートです。
Whether you're asking for a pizza or inviting someone to a movie, the rule is always the
ピザを頼む時や映画に誘う時、ルールはいつも同じです。
same.
カジュアルな場面では、
For casual times with your family and close friends, I want and do you want to are
「I want」や「Do you want to」は全く問題ありません。
totally fine.
しかし、ほとんどの他の状況では、
But for pretty much every other situation, your superpower is I would like for things
「I would like」を使い、行動や招待には「Would you like to」を使います。
And would you like to for actions and invitations?
本当にそれだけ簡単です。そして、これで終わりです。
It really is that simple. And that's a wrap.
これで、より丁寧で、成熟した、そして自信を持って英語を話すための鍵を手に入れました。
You've now have the key to sounding more polite,
最後の質問です。
more mature, and way more confident in English.
この社交的なスーパーパワーを手に入れた今、
So my final question for you is,
どうやってそれを活用しますか？
now that you have this social superpower,
今日は一緒に過ごしてくれてありがとう。